(upbeat music)
- All right, thank you everyone.
We've got a very fun discussion today
about what's been on
the hottest trends of the
last couple months and
Bitcoin Treasury companies.
And I've joined by a true
legend in the Bitcoin space
at a back, better known
for his work around
cryptography and some of
the underpinnings of Bitcoin.
So I kind of wanted to
start there at him like you
had literally a history in
Bitcoin since the beginning
and are much more known for
your technical contributions to Bitcoin.
What kind of a
picture interest in the
financialization and the
Treasury company, Dave?
- Yeah, I mean, I was
actually active trader in the
mid '90s, kind of a day
trader then a value investor.
And certainly interested in
macroeconomics and trading
and the concept of trying to
preserve your savings against inflation.
And so, you know, I sort of put trading
aside while I was focusing on my career
in kind of cryptography
and startup environment.
So they started block stream,
got involved with Bitcoin in 2014.
Block stream was started.
And then of course, Michael
Taylor started his Treasury play.
And so I thought that was
an interesting and valuable
undertaking because
he was sort of leading by
example and then
started a conference series
to try and show other public
market companies how you do it
because, you know,
looking at it from the outside,
you think, well, just buy
Bitcoin and call store it,
but for a public company,
it's not quite that simple
because you have to, you
know, you have to explain
the account, you have to
figure out the accounting.
Maybe you have to use an
independent custodian because
the order to require it and
your shareholders expect it.
So there are a number of things they
had to go through to actually get it done.
And he was interested to sort of promote
that concept to other public companies.
And so, you know, some point in there, I
bought some of his shares because I thought,
you know, I wanted to
support what he's doing.
And if a lot of Bitcoiners
bought a little bit of his shares,
you know, his share, his market
cap is a lot smaller than Bitcoin.
So he wouldn't take that many
Bitcoiners, there are lots of Bitcoiners.
If they bought a little bit of his shares,
you'd be providing some
kind of financial support
that if Wall Street
didn't like his strategy,
the Bitcoiners would buy
the shares off of them, right?
So those are the concepts.
But, now, of course, he famously, you know,
was sort of relentless buyer, you know.
He would buy Bitcoin and he'd
think, "He's got to be out of firepower.
" And then he'd do it again
and again and again again.
So he's really explored the
full spectrum of different ways
that public companies can access capital.
And I think that's been useful.
It surprised me a little bit how on it took
before any other public companies joined.
Now, of course, today,
that's turned around.
And there are a lot of public companies
in a very fast pace of new
entrants coming to the market.
And, you know, I guess
from your entire history
in Bitcoin and all the developments you've
seen, were you expecting the, I guess,
commercial corporate institutional
adoption to happen in this way?
- Yeah, I mean, I think
effectively, you know,
everybody who's investing
in Bitcoin, you know,
they're looking at it
from various perspectives.
But effectively, you're
participating in a
arbitrage between the
mispricing of Bitcoin today
and it's, you know, it's
potential value in the future.
And so effectively,
Bitcoin is the hurdle rate,
meaning that, you know, if
you're doing saving in some
other asset or, you know, for
our professional fund manager,
if they're not keeping up
with Bitcoin's performance
over long-term, you should probably
stop that and buy Bitcoin instead, right?
And so that's not less work.
Second, it's a lot less work, yeah.
And so, I mean, it's
proven to be extremely
difficult to outperform
Bitcoin at the last decade.
And, you know, most people
who invested in startups,
even Bitcoin startups
or did any of the kind of
investing, they typically
realized afterwards,
they should have just bought
Bitcoin and held it, right?
And so with that backdrop, the question
is, how should people operate a company?
And so, you know, Michael
Saylor started that journey
just as a defensive method to protect
the spending power of their cash reserves.
But actually, if you think about it,
the only way for generally
a company to, you know,
match Bitcoin or even
potentially outperform Bitcoin
is to buy Bitcoin and
use the capital markets
to try and increase the Bitcoin per share,
you know, operate their core business,
take some of the
profit, use that's Bitcoin,
use some of the profits
to expand their core
business, their
products, their services.
So, you know, from that point of view, I
think eventually, probably all companies
will be Bitcoin Treasury
companies, eventually.
(upbeat music)
- Well, I think that's the
title of our discussion today.
How do you see that playing
out over the next, you know,
I guess, Saylor's five
years into this strategy,
where do you see this trend
really going over the next five years?
- Yeah, I mean, I think, you
know, one question I've heard
from different kind of
professional investors
who are, you know,
just getting to grips
with the Treasury company playbook
is they wanna ask the question
about how scalable the
Treasury company strategy is.
And by that, they mean if
there are more, you know,
if there are twice as many companies will,
you know, will it become less effective?
Will it saturate the market or something?
And, you know, the scalability
of a trade, at least in arbitrage
is a real phenomena because,
you know, if there's a mispricing,
let's say the Kimchi
premium is an example, right?
So in one country, Bitcoin is
priced a bit more expensively
because of some capital
controls or other factors.
And somebody will try to arbitrage it.
And, you know, if they put enough money
into it, the opportunity will disappear
and they will have made
the market more efficient.
So they're effectively asking a question
like that, but I think the point is here,
the mispricing is rather severe and it's
an extremely large addressable market.
So, because nobody knows today, you know,
exactly what the Bitcoin addressable market
is gonna be ultimately, but you can certainly
see there's a lot of monetary premium
and it's an extremely large
asset classes, like the fixed
income world, real estate and
even, you know, the stock market.
So you can see the US stock market is
highly correlated to monetary expansion.
If you take that factor out of it,
it's approximately flat, in fact, right?
So effectively, probably
what you're looking at
is people just trying to protect their
spending power by buying stocks.
And, you know, if Bitcoin
is able to replace that,
that's actually a better thing
for everybody in France, right?
You get more accurate pricing, you
get better enjoyment from real estate
'cause it's not overpriced
by being an investment asset.
And you get better return on fixed income.
So, I think effectively my
answer to the scalability
is it's extremely scalable
and could absorb, you know,
a lot of the free cash
of some very cash-rich
companies like Berkshire
Hathaway, Apple, Microsoft.
The size of our arbitrage
could swallow that for breakfast
and keep going and take a
few decades to close the gap.
So, from that point of
view, I think it's very scalable
and maybe there is some
sort of positive reinforcement
as well that the market is
still trying to understand
the treasury companies,
trying to understand Bitcoin.
So, if things become
widespread and common spreads,
sometimes what it takes for
people to start to feel comfortable
to understand it, to have
confidence because they
see other people adopting,
other people investing.
So, you know, there are, of course, you
know, for people from a Bitcoin perspective,
they're looking at Bitcoin, the asset class,
electronic cash, self-sovereign money,
and they wonder, you know, what is this
thing with public companies buying Bitcoin?
But, ultimately, you
know, the capital markets
and the ability to
organize economic activity
in the form of a company is a
big part of the world economy.
You know, it basically took human
productivity to where it is today.
So, it's really a basic part of, you know,
modern society and
ability to develop products.
So, I think it's quite natural that companies
are going to want to participate there.
And so, it's just another
part of Bitcoin adoption.
It's a new vector of adoption.
And you can see that
the treasury companies,
collectively, are a good
part of the, you know,
purchasing, you know, the inflow
of new buying within the market.
And, of course, the ETFs are also absorbing
a lot of Bitcoin, quite quickly nowadays.
- Well, I, they certainly have been a strong
sustained bidder in the Bitcoin market,
which benefits the whole
community of holders.
But at the same time,
there has been, you know,
some pushback from the community that, you
know, this kind of corporatism of Bitcoin
is maybe antithetical to the
grassroots community driven
but the cyberpunk ethos
of Bitcoin, if you will.
What's your kind of perspective on that?
- Well, I mean, I, you know, I
was involved with the Cyberpunk's,
a lot of, you know,
decade plus before Bitcoin.
And so I do understand this perspective.
And, you know, the
electronic cash kind of interest
within the Cyberpunk's,
the predates Bitcoin,
was about a similar
concept to what's evolved in
Bitcoin, which is, you
know, it solves sovereignty.
Your asset can't be seized.
Now, of course, the, the
Ecash systems of that time
were effectively what we
would call a stable coin today.
So it didn't really have
an investment aspect.
So Bitcoin has an
additional adoption driver,
which is apart from
the kind of missionless
innovation, unseasonable
asset, bear a cash.
You have also an asset class, which is
another driver because some people will buy
or participate as an investment, but typically
people who get involved with Bitcoin,
it sort of changes them, changes their,
you know, their time preference for their,
and makes, you know, sort of, they
learn things that get interested to learn
about inflation, about
monetary theory and so on.
So I think it ultimately, you know, groups
of humans are organized as companies.
Now, 'cause they're a private companies,
which are, you know, a family
business or a dental practice,
and then you have, you
know, small cap companies
on the stock market
and big public companies
that are doing something much
more ambitious, like, you know, a
company like Intel, which is
making CPUs or AMD and so on, so.
I think it's just the natural phenomena
as Bitcoin continues to be adopted.
I think, you know, the
other sort of surprising thing
in a positive sense is the incentives that
make Bitcoin work originally, you know,
people mining the fact
that the sort of mining
activity is interacting
with the market for Bitcoin,
you know, the incentives are
what's holding it together, right?
And it's interesting to see
how scalable the incentives
have proven to be, which is,
as, you know, the early stages
of nation state adoption, institutional
adoption, you know, now effectively Bitcoin,
whether people expected it or not, has BlackRock and
Larry Fink, rooting for Bitcoin, - A vehicleizing it.
- Yeah.
- Well, we heard a little bit
about your kind of discovery
and sort of strategy, but
since then you've become,
I think, one of the most
prolific highest profile investors
into Bitcoin Treasury
companies around the world,
kind of, when did you
make that jump and what do
you see really big the
international opportunity?
- I mean, I think it's
been interesting, right?
So, you know, it described
how I first got involved
Treasury companies by
trying to sort of philosophically
support the mission that
MicroStrategy was taking
and then, you know,
because I have a bit of a
trading background, got
involved in trading there.
And I think when they first
started the MNAF concept
wasn't really talked about, but,
you know, you couldn't look at it.
You couldn't create
those metrics on past there.
So, you know, I think
then I invested in
Metaplanett, was the next
one, and then more recently
in some of the other European
ones, like capital B and H100.
So, it's quite interesting because different
markets have different opportunities.
There's usually something
specific where a domestic company
is maybe more attractive to the local
investors or the local Bitcoin investors.
And I think that could
be for a few reasons.
One is, you know, perhaps
the local community
knows the management team and they trust
them or there's some cultural aspect to it,
but also there are
typically tax differences.
So, different countries
have different tax rules.
And so, you know, sometimes
there is a tax arbitrage
in the Treasury company
where, you know, the
market doesn't have
Bitcoin ETFs, let's say,
and the tax treatment on
Bitcoin is still out of date.
And so, you see that in
Japan with Metaplanett,
in France also, with capital B, there is
some difference where you can hold shares
that are French stocks in some
kind of tax advantage account,
which you can't do with Bitcoin.
Although other countries
have similar situations going on.
So, that kind of is
effectively a kind of arbitrage.
And, you know, may eventually lead to
improved tax treatment in the country.
And of course, there are now more countries
contemplating or working on approving ETFs.
So, I think in Hong Kong,
for example, last year,
there were three ETFs introduced,
which is fairly new, right?
And I think Japan is
also considering ETFs now
and are not in market yet, and
maybe there's still some work to do.
But it's interesting to
sort of participate in that.
And, at least for me,
I've tended to invest
in companies where I
know the management team
or, you know, have confidence
that the management team
are Bitcoiners, they're gonna
stay on the Bitcoin mission,
and they're gonna use the
capital they raised to buy Bitcoin.
And they're not, like, loose
focus or not investor Bitcoin.
So, really, you wanna, I
mean, from my perspective
because it's a
Bitcoin-related investment,
I wanna have confidence that
they're gonna stay on the mission,
stay focused, and also, I guess, you
know, have the capability to raise money
because it is partly a
capital raising process
that is enabling the companies
to increase their Bitcoin for share.
So, if the team has some
capital raising experience
and capability between
a team or their advisors
or, you know, banking
partners, I think, like, there.
So, yeah, and I think there also
have been a range of investment types.
So, microstrategy
being a first as explored
initially, well, firstly,
these are cash reserves.
Then they took out corporate bonds,
then they moved on to convertible notes,
which are a little bit more
beneficial because they were
selling convertible notes
at 50% conversion premium.
So, they could raise $150
million by Bitcoin without, you
know, immediately, and if the
conversion premium is reached,
then they would only suffer
$100 million worth of conversion.
So, you could see immediately that, even
if they started with a one-time Zen nav,
that would still increase
Bitcoin for share, right?
Which you wouldn't be
able to do with an ATM.
And then, you know, once
the companies do have
an MNAF premium, of course,
they can do ATMs or ATM-like
strategies, an increased
Bitcoin per share of that way.
And metoplanet has been
using moving strike warrants,
capital B has been using ATMs
or something like it in France.
And I think, of course, the last phenomena
has been pioneered by
microstrategy or strategies
that's called today,
again, with the lineup
of different preferred
stocks they put in the market.
You know, they had three
initially with kind of middle,
you know, middling levels
of capital market appetite.
But the last one, STRC or stretch,
actually, they sold quite large amount,
like over 2 billion in a first out of
the gate, which is quite impressive.
The other thing, which I don't know
people are aware is that as well
as the ATM on a common stock,
whether able to work with a banking
partner to sell new shares into the market,
is because the preferred
shares are also listed instruments,
they're able to apply for and get approval
for an ATM on the preferred shares, right?
So I think that that may
not have taken full force yet,
but once the market values
and builds an appetite,
if it does, for STRC,
and I think they already
have ATM approval on it, they
can perhaps more efficiently
and repeatedly raise
capital by selling more STRC
into an ATM market where
without that, they otherwise
have to engage bankers
and find underwriters
or large investment firms
who will buy big tranches of it.
And I think we've seen
some weeks where strategies
run for five ATMs concurrently,
where they're selling
across the entire
universe of listed products.
Well, we're almost out of time, but I wanted
to leave our audience with a little bit.
You touched on the qualitative framework
for a value in these companies, but you've
done a lot of work on the quantitative
side and the valuation methodologies.
And I believe you're the creator
of the months to cover metrics.
So could you explain a little bit
from a quantitative perspective
how you invest or how you think
about value in these companies?
Yeah, I mean, the point with
the months to cover metric
was that if you're investing
in treasury companies
in different markets with
different Mnabs, generally speaking,
a higher Mnab is going to
feel more risky because there's
a prospect that the
Mnab decays, and if it's 10,
it's got a lot further
to fall than if it's two.
And so the question is, how risky is that?
And so one way to risk a just is
to look at the months to cover.
So what that's saying is, if
you buy a treasury company
at five times Mnab, and
they are increasing the
Bitcoin per share, how
long do you have to hold it
for the historic rate of increasing
Bitcoin per share to pay for that premium?
And surprisingly, at the
point I was doing this,
MicroStrategy was, I think
their Mnab was around two,
two and a half, and their month
to cover was about 18 months.
And at that time, Metaplanet
was five, which felt riskier,
but actually the month to cover
were only five or six months.
And so you can see that if
you kind of adjust for that,
it gives you a different
perspective on how to think
about the Mnab, because
I think if you are able
to buy a treasury company
and stay in market long enough
so that you reach par, which
is to say that for every Bitcoin
worth of money that
you use to buy the shares,
you have shares that contain
a Bitcoin worth a Bitcoin,
then you're a kind of one
times Mnab configuration,
even if the company is
carrying a higher Mnab.
And the interesting point is,
you don't have to be an active
trader, at that point you
can hold the company.
And there are a ability to
increase Bitcoin per share.
It is actually working
for you in a passive way,
where you are more insulated
against the Mnab compression.
So of course you never know
if the rate of increasing Bitcoin
per share slows down,
and there's an interplay
between the Mnab and the
ability to increase Bitcoin per share.
So if the Mnab is lower,
generally the capital market
structures are not quite as effective
at adding Bitcoin to the balance sheet.
Well, that's all we have time
for, but thank you very much.
Adam, thank you.
[MUSIC PLAYING]